{
    "id": "d735888a6f324c96823f646807130142",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If we ……………………….. now, we will be there before evening.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she is late, we …………………………… without her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had asked me, I ………………………… you.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had left office at 5 o’clock, she …………………………. here soon.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had met that deadline, she ………………………………… her job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not lose",
                "would not lose",
                "would not have lost"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If they took good care of him, he …………………………..",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would /could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will recuperate",
                "would recuperate",
                "would have recuperated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I didn’t have dance practice today, I ……………………………. shopping with you.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would /could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You would find it easier to travel in Germany, if you ……………………………. a little German.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would /could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "speak",
                "spoke",
                "had spoken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would fix the car myself if I ………………………….. the right tools.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would /could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If we …………………………… enough money, she could not have received that life saving treatment.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "don't collect",
                "didn't collect",
                "hadn't collected"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you eat a lot of vegetables, your immunity …………………………..",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will increase",
                "would increase",
                "would have increased"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you …………………………. that secret, I would not have been in trouble now.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "keep",
                "kept",
                "had kept"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}